Anuj Atri

Amherst, NY - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Anuj-Atri/d70b34c06a4128ae

3+ years of experience leading IT teams offshore as well as onsite.

10+ years of Experience in Design, Development and Implementation of various n-tiered Business applications using Java Technologies in HealthCare, financial, Supply Chain, Travel, education and B2B Domain.

Proficient in Agile Methodologies and Practices.

Extensive experience as Scrum Master and Team Lead.

Successful Offshore Agile Team Management.

Application development experience using multithreading, Serialization, Externalization, Generics & Collections framework and Java Design patterns.

In-Depth experience leading all stages of system development including requirement gathering, analysis, design, development, testing and support.

Extensive experience with ESB using serviceMix, OSGI framework and Apache Camel.

Experience with Continuous Integration of GIT/SVN on Jenkins server using Maven.

Excellent knowledge of MVC Architecture implementing Struts, Tapestry and Spring.

Good Knowledge of Automation testing using Selenium 2.0.

Experience in developing SOAP and REST Web Services.

Hands on experience implementing Responsive Web Design using latest technologies like AngularJS, NodeJs, bootstrap, gulp, typescript, webpack.

Good experience working with front end technologies like JavaScript, JQuery.

Experienced with XML related technologies such as XSL, XSLT, DOM, and SAX..

Good knowledge of Database Concepts.

An effective team player with excellent problem solving and interpersonal skills.

Outstanding leadership abilities; has superior ability to quickly master new concepts.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Sponsorship required to work in the US

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer

NantHealth/Harris Healthcare/ Carefx - February 2011 to Present

Responsibilities: Design and Develop enterprise-level Portal based Healthcare solutions to improve quality of healthcare for patients. Provider Portal is n-tier applications which integrate and enable various data sources using Java/J2ee, Java Servlets, Spring, JSP, Ajax and WPS 6.1.

Application System Engineer

Wells Fargo - Chandler, AZ - July 2009 to January 2011

Description: Worked as a contractor that filled the role of senior Java/C++ developer for the IRX Team. Inbound Returns Express (IRX) system is a windows base 2-tier, client/server application, that is responsible for image-enable the processing of inbound return items (such as checks/image files that have been returned to Wells Fargo) and provides management of incoming cash letters.

Responsibilities:

- System processes automation: starts the day, imports daily cash letters, completes deposit match, automates charge-backs, creates alerts for flagged items, automates balancing of cash letters and exports files.
- Provides tools for Intra-Day and End-of-Day processing.

- Troubleshooting and enhancing C++ legacy modules.
- Provide Dashboard Management Status Tool using GWT.
- Bug fixes, maintenance and production support.
- Designed web service Architecture using Launch Pad Framework.
- Implemented Axis 2.0 Soap Stack to service request-response.
- Used Spring DAO to implement Database interfacing.
- Used Servlets and Filters for previewing images and authentication mechanism.
- Extensive use of Hibernate 3.0 as ORM tool for interfacing with DB.
- Identifying and resolving Weekly Production Support issues.

Technologies and Environment: C++, Java, J2EE, HTML, CSS, XML, Apache Axis1.2, JAXB, EJB3.0, Tapestry 4.1, DOM, JavaScript, AJAX, GWT, Web Sphere Application Server 5.1, IBM DB2, MySql5.0, Hibernate3.0, Servlets, Web Services, JNDI, RAD6.0, MAC OS 10.x.

Software Engineer

ASU - Phoenix, AZ - May 2008 to July 2009

Description: ASU Ad-Framework is designed to be used by ASU specific applications to show subscribed users of different groups with advertisement, alert and announcements specific to there groups, notifying them of required information. Ad-Framework is an open source framework designed to be utilized by any present or future ASU application.

Responsibilities:

- Designed MVC architecture using Tapestry 4.1 framework.
- Used Servlets and Filters for previewing images and authentication mechanism.
- Extensive use of Hibernate 3.0 as ORM tool for interfacing with DB.
- Apache Axis used to send SOAP messages.
- Used JAXB to parse XML documents.
- Used Hibernate Query Language and Hibernate criteria API.
- Implemented Message Driven beans for consuming JMS messages.
- Built Deployment tasks using ANT.
- Performance tuning of SQL queries, stored procedures.
- Used JQuery cluetips for generating Mouse-over previews.
- Advance use of DOM functions, JavaScript, AJAX and XML.

Technologies and Environment: Java, J2EE, HTML, CSS, XML, Apache Axis1.2, JAXB, EJB3.0, Tapestry 4.1, DOM, JavaScript, AJAX, Web Sphere Application Server 5.1, Oracle 11.5, MySql5.0, Hibernate3.0, Servlets, Web Services, JNDI, RAD6.0, MAC OS 10.x.

Client:

Arizona State University

Software Engineer

Corpus INC - July 2007 to May 2008

July07 to May08

Description: SCMetrix is a benchmarking application which offers hospitals a benchmarking and Performance measurement tool for focused performance improvement initiatives in the healthcare Industry. SCMetrix utilizes the importance of measuring value drivers and implementation of best Practices in supply chain operations.

Responsibilities:

- Team management experience performing client interaction, conducting requirement gathering, designing use-case diagrams, textual and requirement analysis, designing project plan and assigning responsibilities.
- Used component based J2EE framework, Tapestry 4.1 to design MVC architecture.
- Designed Rich GUI using Flex 2.0 to analyze input data.
- Developed Stateless Session beans for crucial business logic.
- Implemented Servlet filters for improving Authentication mechanism.
- Used Hibernate 3.0 for Interfacing with underlying Datasource.
- Provided AJAX support to web application using DOM, JavaScript and XML.
- Use of DOJO Framework for Tooltips.
- Used Hibernate Query Language and Criteria API to instantiate Hibernate Objects.
- Extensive use of SQL/PL-SQL for Database Management.
- Designed JUnit Test cases for automated testing.

Technologies and Environment: Java, J2EE, HTML, CSS, XML, AJAX, DOM, EJB 3.0, Flex, Tapestry 4.1, JavaScript, MQ Series, Web Sphere Application Server 5.1, JUnit4.4, Oracle10g, Hibernate3.0, RAD6.0, MACOS 10.x.

Java Developer

Wyndham Jade - Plano, TX - May 2006 to June 2007

Project Name: SelfReg

Description: SelfReg is a web based application. Application allowed Web-users to Register and book housing for various conventions and incentive shows organized by Wyndham Jade.

Responsibilities:

- Support Existing application and enhancement on coded modules.
- Used Struts1.2 to design work flow of web application.
- Extensive use of J2EE design patterns like MVC, decorator and singleton.
- Developed Entity beans for accessing underlying database systems.
- Setup end-to-end Development Environment.
- Used DOM methods extensively to modify HTML dynamically for AJAX support.
- Configured Web Logic 9.2 server for connection pooling and Data Sources etc.
- Automated Scheduled Deployment procedure on concurrency with CVS updates and Weblogic redeployment.
- Handful use of SQL, PL/SQL.
- Vast experience dealing with client and inter-Departmental requirements.
- Performance evaluation for JBDC connections, extensive debugging of memory leaks and optimized prepared statements for performance Enhancement.

Technologies & Environment: Java, J2EE, EJB 3.0, JDBC, JSP, XML, HTML, Struts, JavaScript, DOM, AJAX, Weblogic 9.2, Oracle10g, Windows XP.

Web Developer

CITICAPITAL-Citigroup - Irving, TX - May 2005 to April 2006

Financial Application - CONNECT

Description: CONNECT is a financial application allowing user to authenticate using user credentials, navigate through different menus, maintain session and cookies. It uses XSL and XML to parse the output and use Struts framework to keep the workflow of web application.

Responsibilities:

- Used SAX and DOM API for parsing the input and output XML documents.
- Used Virtual SourceSafe on UNIX system for version control.
- Used Java Security API to provide encrypted Authentication Procedure.
- Used Struts open source Architecture to Design Workflow for Web Application.
- Written PL/SQL procedures, functions, and packages for intensive database transactions.
- Worked with ANT and developed separate build files for development, UAT (User Accessibility Testing) and production environments
- Deployed Entity and Session beans in Web Sphere Application Server.
- Extensively used Log4j logging in the application.
- Client side validations done using JavaScript.

Technologies & Environment: J2EE, Java, Servlets, PL/SQL, EJB 3.0, Oracle9i, JSP 1.2, Web Sphere Application Server 5.1, Web Services, ANT, Visual Source Safe, SAAJ, Log4J, AIX, IIS Web Server.

Java Developer

ATCIS, Fort-Worth, Texas - May 2004 to September 2004

Project: Sales Tracking and Reporting System

Description: Project was to keep track of Sales and reengineered products shipping and tracking information. Various clients as well as Device information was created, stored and tracked using the internet/Intranet user interface.

Responsibilities:

- Generated User interface Templates using JSP, CSS, HTML, and DHTML.
- Client side Validation was done using JavaScript.
- Designing the software modules implementing Struts framework that is based on the Model View Controller design pattern.
- Developed and Deployed Enterprise Java Beans that handles Database interaction with oracle 9i database.
- Used Servlets 2.3 for processing business rules.
- Used Microsoft Visual Source Safe (VSS) for version control.

Technologies and Environment: Java, Struts1.2, Servlets, EJB, JSP, Oracle 9i, SQL, Stored Procedures, Windows XP, UNIX.

Software Developer

Hexa Information Systems - New Delhi, Delhi - January 2002 to June 2003

Project: Simulation of ATM

Description: The aim of the project was to design a simulation tool, which can help measure, the speed, analyze and maintain high-speed telecommunication networks. Team was responsible to read real time traffic and feed the data to designed GUI.

Responsibilities:

• Involved in the customization, bug fixing and testing and delivery phase of the project.

- Used socket programming to connect and read information from servers.
- Preparing Technical requirement documents from business requirements from the customer when a trouble report is raised.
- Worked on the authenticate module in the server to validate the client service requests.

Environment: C++, UNIX.

Publication:

• Ram Dantu, Gabriel Clothier, Anuj Atri (2006) EAP methods for wireless networks. Computer Standard and Interfaces Vol 29 (3):289-301.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science

University of North Texas - Denton, TX August 2003 to August 2005

BS in Computer Science

PCCS - Noida, Uttar Pradesh October 1998 to July 2002

SKILLS

JAVA (10+ years), J2EE (10+ years), AJAX (2 years), JSP (8 years), JAVASCRIPT (6 years), Spring (7 years), Web Services (4 years), Design Pattern (10+ years), Application Development (10+ years)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Java/J2EE Development: Core Java, JSR 168, JSP, Servlet, EJB, JDBC,

JNDI, Hibernate

Frameworks: Struts 2.0, Spring 3.0, AngularJs, JQuery, Bootstrap, MVC,

Junit, Selenium, Tapestry

Web Development

Flex, JavaScript,, DOM, DOJO, HTML, CSS, GWT, XML, XSL, Web Services, Apache Axis, JAXB, AJAX, WSDL, UDDI, SOAP, HTTP, Apache Digester, Jersey, JSON, Log4j.

Designing and Modelling

Design Patterns Dependency Injection, MVC, Factory, abstract Factory, Singleton Pattern, and Adapter.

Languages

C, C++, Vc++, Java, PL/SQL.

Web/Application Servers

IIS, Apache Tomcat, Weblogic, WebSphere, WPS

Databases and Tools

SQL Server, Oracle, DB2, MySql, TOAD, Aqua Data Studio.

IDE

STS, IntelliJ, Eclipse, RAD7.0, Netbeans, JDeveloper

Productivity Tools

VSS, CVS, Perforce, SVN, Adobe Photoshop, Director 8, Flash, Macromedia Dreamweaver and GIT.

Build and Integration

ANT, Maven and Jenkins.